DAVID MENZIES



- Davidmenziesjr1222@gmail.com
- 845-978-9870
- Middletown, NY 10940
- Online Digital Resume

SKILLS

- Adaptable and Flexible
- Strong Communication and Interpersonal Skills
- Attention to Detail
- Systems Engineering
- Revit, Autocad, Rhino
- Motivated self-starter
- LEED

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Performance-oriented Sales Leader offering exceptional record of achievement over 4-year career. Tenacious manager with strategic and analytical approach to solving problems, bringing in customers and accomplishing profit targets. Talented in identifying and capitalizing on emerging market trends and revenue opportunities. In addition, a talented student with industrious and systematic approach to learning information. Open and clear worker with disciplined execution and methodical nature. Extensive knowledge of research and software skills.

WEBSITE, PORTFOLIO, PROFILES

- https://www.linkedin.com/in/david-menzies-657005220/
- https://drive.google.com/file/d/1dJZX9_J2AoUtgPVcvW mbKlD530fVb_tH/view?usp=sharing

WORK HISTORY

Walmart - Front End Associate

Middletown, NY • 03/2019 - Current

- Established customer satisfaction by answering questions about store policies and addressing customer concerns.
- Welcomed and engaged customers, offering assistance with locating or retrieving merchandise.

Footlocker Retail - Retail Sales Lead

Middletown, United States • 06/2018 - Current

- Coached sales associates in product specifications, sales incentives and selling techniques, significantly increasing customer satisfaction ratings.
- Submitted reports to senior management to establish business decision-making and planning.
- Recruited, hired and trained dozen of associates to develop into productive team members with excellent product knowledge.
- Developed a team into being number one store of the year
- Over performed expected year results and won multiple company contests

EDUCATION/AWARDS/ ORGANIZATION

New York Institute of Technology
Old Westbury, NY • Expected in 2024

BSAT & Masters in

Architecture: Architecture

- Member of National Honor Society
- Received T.K. Steele Scholarship
- Received National Footlocker Scholarship
- Member of AIAS mentor program
- President's List 2022
- Dean's List 2019-2021

Middletown High School Middletown, NY • 06/2019

Advanced Regents Diploma
College Level Classes Project
Lead the Way (PLTW) -,
Engineering Design And
Development, Civil
Engineering and Architecture

- Member of National Honor Society
- Dean's List 2016-2019
- Received Ruthie
 Dino-Marshall Memorial
 Scholarship
- Received World Jam Production Scholarship
- Awarded 24th best GPA in class
- Relevant Coursework
 Completed: Syracuse SUPA classes & PLTW

Middletown High School Basketball Camp 01/2015 - 01/2019

Coached younger kids not only basketball skills but also ways on being a leader on and off the court. I organized drills, group activities and developed a timely mannered schedule for everything to run smoothly.